能把黄芥末酱递给我吗?
Would you pass the mustard?
当然
Sure.
嘿 想听黄芥末酱的趣味知识吗?
Hey, want to hear a fun fact about mustard?
你是不是想说给黄芥末酱带来风味的是葡糖异硫氰酸盐
Is it that the glucosinolates which give mustard its flavor
甘蓝族植物也会散发
were evolved by the cabbage family
同样的化学物质来抵御毛毛虫吗?
as a chemical defense against caterpillars?
对
Yeah.
那是挺有趣的
Well, that was fun.
干得好 Leonard
Good for you, Leonard.
你们好
Hey, there.
嘿 你们来早了
Hey, you're early.
电影再过一个小时才会开场
The movie doesn't start for an hour.
其实 我们不去看电影
Actually, we're not going to the movies.
我们是来绑架你的
We are here to kidnap you.
你们在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
你当初私奔了 所以我们没机会
Well, you eloped and we didn't get a chance
为你办个告别单身派对
to throw you a bachelor party,
所以车已经在楼下等着了
so there's a van downstairs
我们要带你去个
and we're here to take you
神秘的地方度周末
to a surprise location for the weekend.
我觉得这不算是绑架
Well, I'd hardly call this kidnapping.
眼罩呢?
Where's the blindfold?
胶带呢?
Where's the duct tape?
你们打电话给我
Where's the part
要求我付赎金 而我努力拖延
where you call me and demand ransom
不让你们挂电话 但你们就在
and I try to keep you on the phone,
我追踪到位置前几秒挂断了
but you hang up seconds before I can trace it
接着我说"我上年纪了 受不了这种刺激"的部分呢?
and then I say, "I'm getting too old for this crud"?
我们什么时候走?
When do we leave?
立刻
Right now.
对 Penny帮你打包好了
Yeah, Penny packed you a bag.
好吧
Wow, okay.
你真的打算上车 让这俩人
You're seriously going to get in a van and let these two
带你去个未知的地方
take you to an unknown destination
度过整个周末?
for an entire weekend?
不止是他 你也得一起去
Oh, not just him. You're coming, too.
你们打算怎么逼我呢?
Oh, and how do you think you're going to get me to do that?
放开我!
Unhand me!
太可笑了!
This is ridiculous!
我就说要用胶带封住他的嘴!
I told you to put tape on his mouth!
我也说了 他咬我!
And I told you he bit me!
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第3集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 狂写作业的凤梨酥   校对: UUUUUU
翻译: 酱油影 肉肉 猫呗 夏至未寒 凤梨酥
违背我的意志带上我
It's bad enough I'm being taken
已经够糟了
against my will.
我不明白为什么非得坐
I don't see why it has to be in
这种嬉皮士的可移动性爱地下城
some hippie's mobile sex dungeon.
Sheldon 你马上就会发现
Well, Sheldon, there's something about this van
这辆面包车的有趣之处了
that you're going to find very interesting.
是用梅毒作燃料的吗?
It runs on syphilis?
这辆面包车的主人正是你崇拜的
This van was owned and driven by your personal
物理界英雄...
physics hero...
理查德·费曼
Richard Feynman.
- 不会吧  - 就是!
- No.  - Yeah!
我的朋友帮我借到的
A buddy of mine let me borrow it.
这是费曼的车?
This was Feynman's van?
那太赞了
That's so cool.
对 自从他开过这车后 里面东西就都没换过
Yeah, nothing's been changed since he drove it.
我打赌 他用这辆车接过很多可爱的毕业生
I bet he picked up a lot of cute grad students in this bad boy.
对 还和他们讨论物理问题!
Yeah, and talked about physics with them!
你能给个提示 我们这是要去哪儿吗?
So, are you gonna give us a clue where we're headed?
好 我想想...
Uh, okay, let's see...
他们那儿有辣的食物
They've got spicy food
你可能会拉肚子
and there's a chance you'll get diarrhea.
印度
India.
是能开车去的地方
We can drive there.
你家?
Your house?
我们要去墨 喜 哥!
We are going to Meh-he-co!
正好 我还没去过呢!
Fun, I've never been there!
Leonard 别被骗了!
Leonard, don't be fooled!
我是德州人...
I'm from Texas...
墨喜哥在西班牙语里就是"墨西哥"
Meh-he-co is Spanish for Mexico.
墨西哥怎么了?
What's wrong with Mexico?
那里有流浪乐队 野狗
Uh, mariachi bands, wild dogs,
还有到处跳的豆子 因为里头有虫子
beans that jump around 'cause there's a worm inside.
好 冷静
Okay, calm down.
这个周末有个主题
There's a theme to this weekend.
我们驾驶费曼的面包车去墨西哥
We are going to Mexico in Feynman's van
住在费曼用诺贝尔奖金
to stay at the vacation house Feynman bought
买的度假屋里
with the money from his Nobel Prize.
盐酸洛哌丁胺万岁!
Viva la Imodium!
耶耶耶!
Ay-ay-ay!
拜托 Leonard都去告别单身派对了
Come on, Leonard's doing bachelor stuff.
你确定不要我们带你去脱衣酒吧吗?
You sure we can't take you to a strip club?
不用 如果我要看跳舞裸男
Nah, if I want to see a naked dancing man,
只需要在Leonard洗澡的时候冲下厕所
I just flush the toilet while Leonard's in the shower.
- 嗨  - 嘿
- Hi.  - Hey.
我知道你们不想太张扬
I know we're not making a fuss,
但秉承告别单身派对的精神
but in the spirit of bachelorette parties,
我烤了男人生殖器形状的曲奇饼
I made cookies in the shape of male genitals.
你真的用不着...
You really didn't have to...
我的天啊!
Whoa!
活灵活现
That is anatomic.
谢谢
Thank you.
血管是软糖条做成的
The veins are gummy worms.
看啊
Oh, look,
犹太人行割礼
还分犹太人和非犹太人
Jewish and gentile.
面揉多了
I had extra dough.
是Leonard的短信
Oh, that's Leonard.
他说他们准备穿过国界了
He said they're about to cross the border.
希望他们不会在墨西哥玩得太疯
I hope the boys don't get too crazy in Mexico.
哦 是啊 看好你的女儿
Oh, yeah, right. Lock up your daughters
不然Sheldon就会给她们讲
or Sheldon might lecture them
北美各国互通农产品免税的法案, 旨在促进农业经济发展
北美自由贸易法案了
about the North American Free Trade Agreement.
那晚可真是漫长啊
Boy, that was a long night for me.
啊哦
Uh-oh.
根据墨西哥海关网站的要求
According to this Mexican Customs Web site,
游客不能携带超过五张激光光盘
visitors may not bring more than five laser discs,
20张CD
20 compact discs
或12盘录像带入境
or 12 VHS tapes..
我们根本没有那些
We don't have any of those.
你怎么知道?
How can you be sure?
当费曼开这辆车时录像带很流行呢
VHS was king when Feynman drove this van.
说不定在秘密夹层里还有好多
For all we know, there are hidden compartments
简方达锻炼的视频呢
lousy with Jane Fonda workout videos.
如果真有秘密夹层的话
If there was a hidden compartment,
你不觉得你早就被塞进去了吗?
don't you think you'd be stuffed in it by now?
我们都打了黄热病疫苗了吧?
Are we all up to date on our yellow fever inoculations?
去墨西哥又没必要打黄热病疫苗
You don't need a yellow fever shot to go to Mexico.
不怕一万就怕万一
You can never be too careful.
佛罗里达州的一个迪士尼主题公园
去年我去艾波卡特时候就打了
I got one last year before I went to Epcot.
Penny 婚后的生活怎么样?
So, Penny, how's married life?
太棒了
Oh, it's good.
我只是希望Leonard能鼓起勇气
I just wish Leonard would work up the courage
告诉Sheldon他要搬来住了
to tell Sheldon he's moving in here.
你们还没有住在一起?
You guys still aren't living together?
在一起啊 我是说 他在这睡觉
We are. I mean, he sleeps here.
但Sheldon迟早会因为
But it's only a matter of time
做了噩梦
before Sheldon has a bad dream
然后爬上Leonard的床
and tries to climb into bed
发现里面塞的全是枕头
with the Leonard-shaped pile of pillows.
说起Sheldon
Speaking of Sheldon,
你的单身生活怎么样?
how's single life treating you?
还好吧 我猜
Fine, I guess.
我一直在关注自己
I've been focusing on me.
我打算把我的衣柜换了
I was thinking about changing my wardrobe.
- 不错啊!  - 太好了!
- Yes!  - Good for you!
但之后我决定不去因为某个男人而
But then I decided I don't want to go changing who I am
改变自己
just because of some man.
- 好  - 不错
- Yes.  - Good for you.
其实在分手后改变自己
You know, it is normal
是很正常的事啊
to want to change your look after a breakup.
其实 我打算稍微改变一下
Actually, I was thinking of making one small change.
- 你的毛衣?  - 你的眼镜?
- Your sweater?  - Your glasses?
- 你的发型?  - 你的鞋!
- Your hair?  - Your shoes!
是打耳洞
Piercing my ears.
- 哦  - 哦
- Oh. -  Oh.
你之前真的没打过吗?
You really never had that done?
我妈妈和我说只有
My mom said pierced ears
妓女 海盗和精灵才打耳洞
were for whores, pirates and genies.
但你现在是个成年人了啊
Okay, well, you're a grown woman now.
我知道 但Sheldon
I know, but Sheldon had this clause
在恋爱协议里面有一条就是
in the Relationship Agreement
禁止对脸动任何手脚
forbidding cosmetic surgery
除非是整成克林贡人
unless it's to look like a Klingon.
我们把你带到商场去打耳洞吧
We'll take you to the mall to get it done.
为什么? 我在这就能打
Why? I can do it right here.
真的吗?
Really?
- 你有耳洞枪吗?  - 没有
- You have a piercing gun?  - No.
你只需要一根针还有冰块
All you need is a needle and an ice cube.
我之前打过差不多 十几次吧
I've done it, like, a dozen times.
我不知道啊
Oh, I don't know.
别怕 我会很温柔的
Oh, come on. I'll be gentle.
让我夺走你耳朵的第一次吧
Let me take your ear virginity.
这派对太奇葩了
This party's weird.
嘿 注意速度
Hey, watch your speed.
我听说墨西哥警察专查游客
I hear the Mexican police target tourists.
啊 没问题
Oh, not a problem.
如果发生什么事
If anything goes down,
就把Koothrappali拽到驾驶员座位上
we just put Koothrappali in the driver's seat
然后给他头上戴一顶阔边帽(墨西哥服饰)
and slap a sombrero on his head.
哥们 你一句话能得罪多少种族啊?
Dude, how many races can you offend in a single breath?
我不知道
I don't know.
你和我看过奥运会吗?
Have you watched the Olympics with me?
Sheldon 你能相信我们正坐在
Sheldon, can you believe that we're driving in a van
二十世纪最伟大的科学家的
that was owned by one of the greatest scientific minds
旅行车里吗?
of the 20th century?
就像蝙蝠侠战车一样
It's like the Batmobile.
如果蝙蝠侠是真的
If Batman was real
并是个物理学家
and a physicist
而且他车非常丑
and his car wasn't cool.
真是令人惊奇
It is extraordinary.
说不定我们能蹭到一点他的天赋
Perhaps some of his mojo will rub off on us.
坐着这车到他海滨别墅的路上
Maybe between this and his beach house,
我们会有重大的启发
we will be inspired to greatness.
我一般都不信那些鬼神之说
I usually don't put too much stock in charms and talismans.
但是 我得承认
However, even I must admit
感受着理查德·费曼陷下去的屁股印儿
feeling Richard Feynman's
托住我自己的屁股...
butt dent cupping my own bottom...
的确是让创造的精华奔涌飞溅呢
that does get the creative juices flowing.
嘿 这车还是要还的
Hey, I have to return this van.
创造的精华还是留在你的内裤里吧
Keep your creative juices in your pants.
怎么回事?
What was that?
应该是坏了个轮胎
I think it's a tire.
要是有土匪朝我们开枪怎么办?
What if it's banditos shooting at us?
要是我们被绑架了怎么办?
What if we get kidnapped?
要是我们被困在工厂里 余生只能
What if we end up in a factory making Bart Simpson pi?atas
靠做辛普森玩偶讨生活怎么办?!
for the rest of our lives?!
只是轮胎坏了
It's the tire.
喂 Leonard?
Leonard?
怎么了?
What?
我上年纪了 受不了这种刺激
I am getting too old for this crud.
Amy 我看到你脸书上的感情状态
Amy, I noticed your status still says
还是写着"恋爱中"
"in a relationship" on Facebook.
你说得对
You're right.
我应该让我所有的脸书的好友知道这事
I should probably let all of my Facebook friends know.
Penny 我现在是单身狗了
Penny, I'm no longer in a relationship.
你有没有把你的改成 "已婚"?
Did you change yours to "married" yet?
不 还没有
Uh, no, not yet.
有一些人我还没告诉
There's still a few people I haven't told personally.
什么人?
Who?
只不过是我父母
Oh, just my parents
和我全家人
and my entire family.
什么?
What?
为什么?
Why?
我不想伤害我的爸爸
Well, I don't want to hurt my dad.
他总是想在婚礼上
You know, he always wanted
和女儿一起跳舞
to dance with his daughter at her wedding.
他没在你姐姐的婚礼上跳舞吗?
What about your sister's wedding?
本来开始跳了 然后她的羊水破了
They started to, then her water broke.
假如被他发现我们私奔去结婚
You know, if he finds out we eloped,
会伤透他的心的
it's gonna break his heart.
你觉得这事能瞒他多久?
How long do you think you can keep it from him?
对啊 你不觉得拖得越久越糟糕吗?
Yeah, isn't it gonna get worse the longer you wait?
不一定啊
Well, not necessarily.
我爸爸年纪也不小了
You know, Dad's not getting any younger,
如果拖得够久
so if I wait long enough,
到时候我就告诉他 是他牵着我走过了红毯
I'll just tell him he walked me down the aisle
画面非常感人
and it was magical.
你怎么学会换轮胎的?
When did you learn how to change a tire?
每位有自尊的绅士都应该知道怎么换
Every self-respecting gentleman should know how
这样在路边碰到有困难的姑娘
in case he comes across a damsel in distress
他就能去帮忙了
by the side of the road.
要是给我看到一只蝎子
If I see one scorpion,
我就爬上你们的肩膀
I am getting on someone's shoulders
我也不下来了
and never coming down.
你的姑娘在那呢
And there's your damsel.
哇 这一个卡的好紧
Wow, this one's really stuck.
你旋的方向是对的吗?
Are you turning it the right way?
不
No.
我把其他四个都换下来了
I took the other four off
到这一个 我就想
and when I got to this one, I thought,
"老这么旋太没意思了 不如换个口味吧"
"You know, I'm in a rut. Let's shake things up."
让我试试
Here, let me try.
你说得对 换个方向确实旋不下来
You're right, it doesn't turn the other way.
就这样啦
There you go.
耳洞打好了!
You're all done!
感觉挺不错的
That wasn't so bad.
好漂亮
Nice.
天啊 要是我妈妈看到我
Boy, if my mom could see me now,
她要把我锁进罪孽柜里面壁思过了
she'd lock me in the sin closet.
你在开玩笑吧?
That's a joke, right?
说实话 她才是玩笑
Actually, the joke was on her.
我还能从柜子缝里看电视呢
I could still see the TV through the slats.
我终于明白
I'm starting to see
为什么你和你妈妈的关系不亲密了
why you and your mom aren't very close.
但是她要是结婚了
Bet she'd still tell her
她还是会告诉妈妈的
if she got married.
你抓着这事不放手了吗?
You're not gonna let this go, are you?
他们不知道这事让人很伤心
Well, it's kind of sad that they don't know.
我是说 他们都爱Leonard
I mean, they love Leonard.
好吧 你们要我打电话吗?
Fine, you want me to call?
我打电话
I'll call.
为什么我会这么紧张?
Why am I so nervous?
这可以理解
It's understandable.
Amy告诉妈妈她和Sheldon分手的时候也很害怕
Amy was afraid to tell her mom she broke up with Sheldon.
是吗? 后来怎么样了?
Yeah? How did it go?
她有没有逼你爬进
Did she make you crawl
分手抽屉面壁思过?
into the breaking-up drawer?
呃 实际上 说实话...
Uh, well, actually, to be honest...
我还没告诉她
I-I haven't told her yet.
你刚才让我那么不好过
You've been giving me a hard time
而这事你还没告诉你妈妈?
and you haven't even told your mom about Sheldon?
我失血太多有点头晕
I'm feeling a little dizzy from all the blood loss.
听不清你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
好吧 我在往家里打电话
Fine. I'm calling home,
但是等我打完了 你就给你妈妈打电话
but when I'm done, you're calling your mother.
对你来说容易
Easy for you to say.
你又不用拿这个姿势看新闻联播
You never had to watch 60 Minutes like this.
嗨 爸爸
Hey, Daddy.
嗨 伙计
Hey, slugger.
我闺女怎么样了啊?
How's my girl?
呃 挺好的 妈妈在吗?
Uh, good. Is Mom around?
呃 她带你弟弟去庆祝了
Ah, she took your brother out to celebrate.
他刚刚拿到了他的第十个戒酒一月纪念
He just got his tenth one-month sober chip.
她会给他做成一条项链的
Yeah, she's gonna make him a little necklace.
好吧 我一会儿再和她说
Okay, I'll talk to her later.
呃 爸爸 我有事要跟你讲
Uh, Dad, there's something I need to tell you.
我和Leonard结婚了
Leonard and I got married.
你结婚了?
You did?
什么时候?
When?
在上星期 对不起 我应该提前告诉你的
Last week. I'm sorry, I should've told you.
当时就是一时冲动
It was a spur of the moment thing.
我感觉糟糕透了
I feel terrible.
请千万别太失望
Please don't be too disappointed.
那你高兴吗?
Are you happy?
非常高兴
Very.
Leonard简直太棒了
Leonard is so great.
好吧 那我也为你感到高兴
Well, then I'm happy for you.
呃 谢谢你 爸爸
Aw, thank you, Daddy.
你对我真好
That means so much.
呃 如果你一定要告诉某人
Well, I understand it's hard
一些可能让他不高兴的事情
to tell someone something
那种感觉很难受
if you think it's gonna upset 'em.
这就是
It is.
你是这世界上最好的爸爸
You're the best dad ever.
是的 呃 先等等
Yeah. Uh, hold that thought.
我也有些新闻没告诉你
I've been sitting on a little news myself.
呃 什么啊?
Well, what is it?
你知道我那个给拖拉机用的碎土器吗?
You know that rototiller I got for the tractor?
不知道啊
No.
呃 你真应该看看
Oh, you should see it.
那机器简直棒极了
It is a beautiful piece of machinery.
不过 呃...
Anyway, uh...
我倒车时不小心碾到了你的宠物猪
I backed over your pet pig with it.
"月舞"吗?
Moondance?
是的 呃 它以后没法再跳舞了
Yeah, he's, uh, not dancing anymore.
你杀了我的猪?
You killed my pig?
我没有杀他
I did not kill him.
是在兽医那死的
The vet took care of that.
什么时候?
When?
呃... 大概是十 十二个月以前吧
Oh... ten, 12 months ago.
你竟然瞒了我一整年?!
You didn't tell me for a year?!
呃 有其女必有其父吗 对吧?
Well, apple doesn't fall far from the tree, does it?
我爱你 伙计
Love ya, slugger.
我得挂了!
Gotta go!
呃 Amy 该你了
Okay, Amy, your turn.
你这是干嘛?
What are you doing?
这个叫做拉玛泽呼吸
It's called Lamaze breathing.
可以帮你用力
It helps you push.
好吧
Great.
那你用子宫推好了
He's pushing with his uterus.
应该有个更容易的办法把它弄下来的
There's got to be a smarter way of removing it.
是的 这不过就是个物理学问题罢了
Yeah, this is nothing more than a physics problem.
对
Right.
阿基米德曾经说了
Archimedes once said,
"给我一根足够长的的杠杆
"Give me a 'leever' long enough
和一个支点
and a fulcrum on which to place it,
我就能撬动地球"
and I shall move the world."
当然
Of course.
我们只需要找点原材料
All we need is to find stuff
把这个杠杆做出来就行了
to make a "leever" big enough to fix this.
一点不错
Exactly.
我敢打赌这附近有东西
I'll bet there's something around here
能当这个"撬棍"
that could be a "lehver."
让我找找 "撬棍"在哪呢...
Let's see, a "lehver," a "lehver"...
大家等一下!
Everybody hold on!
我们按顺序一个个解决问题
Let's take this problem one step at a time.
首先 我们得决定
First, we need to decide
我们是叫它杠杆还是撬棍
whether we're calling it leever or lehver.
等我们决定叫它杠杆之后
And the sooner we decide it's leever,
就可以卷起袖子... 而不是衣袖...
the sooner we can roll up our sleeves... not slehves...
然后再干活
and get to work.
我们就"永久的"在这呆着吧
We're gonna be here "foreever."
真是多谢了 姐妹们
Thanks a lot, guys.
我们做什么了?
What did we do?
在我打电话之前
Before I made that call,
我的小猪还是活蹦乱跳的
my pig was alive and happy
在泥地里打滚
and rolling around in the mud.
现在它被非法埋在后院里
Now he's illegally buried in our backyard
和我的曾祖母一起
next to my great-grandmother.
真的吗?
Really?
他们没有把它吃了?
They didn't eat him?
没有
No.
它是我们家庭里的一员好嘛
He was a beloved member of the family.
早餐肉家庭是吗?
The breakfast meat family?
这一点儿都不好笑
It's not funny.
该你了 打电话给你妈妈
You're up. Call your mother.
呃 还是等一会吧
Oh, maybe later.
我现在为你的小猪之死感到很伤心
Your pig dying made me sad.
还有点饿
And a little hungry.
快点 拿电话
Phone, now.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
我打还不行
Fine.
喂 妈
Hi, Mom.
你得先拨号吧
Try dialing.
被你发现了 是吧?
You saw that, huh?
喂 妈 你最近怎么样?
Hi, Mom. How are you doing?
哦 那就好
Oh, good.
工作怎么样?
How's work?
那真不错
That's nice.
我挺好的
I'm fine.
那个 我就是想问一下
Hey, listen, I've been meaning to ask,
Doe阿姨和Florence阿姨为什么关系不太好?
how come Aunt Doe and Aunt Florence never got along?
真是够了... 把电话给我
Okay, just... give me that.
Amy和Sheldon分手了
Amy broke up with Sheldon,
她还打了耳洞
she got her ears pierced
还让我们吃鸡鸡饼!
and she made us eat penis cookies!
稍等
Hang on.
她想找你谈谈
She wants to talk to you.
我觉得杠杆好像没什么作用
I don't think the lever's working.
为什么这么说?
What makes you say that?
我们一定可以找到别的办法的
There's gotta be something else we could try.
这要是在星际迷航的世界里
If this was Star Trek,
我们就可以用相位枪打爆它了
we could use a phaser to blast it off.
不行 光束太粗了
No, it's too broad of a beam.
需要更精确的东西
You'd need something more precise,
比如超人的热成像仪
like Superman's heat vision.
哦哦 还有绿灯侠的戒指
Ooh, the Green Lantern's ring
可以变出一只绿巨手拧开螺丝
could make a big green hand that unscrews it.
要是你需要绿巨手的话
If you need a green hand,
为什么不直接用绿巨人?
why not just use the Hulk?
拜托 绿巨人的脾气那么暴躁
Oh, please, the Hulk would never get
绝对过不了国境线
across the border with that temper.
各位 你们听我说
Guys, excuse me,
找复仇者联盟里的人来帮忙
not that calling one of the Avengers
当然没什么问题
isn't a perfectly reasonable choice,
可我们是科学家
but we're scientists.
你们难道不觉得我们应该运用真正的科学
Don't you think we can figure this out
来解决这个问题吗?
using actual science?
没错 我们可以运用科学知识的
Yes, we could use science.
可这是你的告别单身趴啊
But it's your bachelor party.
别那么认真
Lighten up.
科学原理: 冲击 (指由爆炸带来的冲击)
# 我们将 #
# We will #
# 我们将冲击你 #
# We will percussive shock you #
# 我们将 #
# We will #
# 我们将冲击你 #
# We will percussive shock you #
# 你就是个男孩 #
# Buddy you're a boy #
# 在街上 #
# Make a big noise #
# 大吵大闹 #
# Playin' in the street #
# 以后你总会长大成人 #
# Gonna be a big man someday #
# 脸上糊着泥巴 你真丢人 #
# You got mud on your face, you big disgrace #
# 还踢着易拉罐到处乱跑 #
# Kickin' your can all over the place. #
我过目不忘
I have an eidetic memory.
有的时候真不是什么好事
Sometimes it's a curse.
科学原理: 热力膨胀
我一直不知道
I had no idea
玉米片是这么好的燃料
tortilla chips were such a good fuel source.
因为它基本上就是溶在脂肪里的碳水化合物
They're basically pure hydrocarbons soaked in fat.
但愿那个螺帽能变松点
Let's hope the lug nut expands.
要是我们烧玉米片的味道引来动物怎么办?
What if that burning food attracts animals?
我们有足够多的食物喂动物
We have plenty of food for the animals.
- 是吗?  - 是啊
- We do?  - Yep.
毕竟有个一米八的穿着闪电侠T恤的汉子呢
A six-foot wiener in a Flash T-shirt.
你这样就不好了吧
That's not very nice.
这是个告别单身趴 别那么认真嘛
It's a bachelor party. Lighten up.
科学原理: 加速腐蚀
什么东西这么难闻?
What is that awful smell?
点燃的墨西哥辣酱
It's burning salsa.
我希望里面的酸和盐
I'm hoping the acidity and salinity
再加上电 能够腐蚀掉螺帽
combined with electricity will corrode the lug nut off.
这办法太有创造性了
What an innovative solution.
我以前小看你在麻省理工的学历了
Perhaps I don't give your MIT education enough credit.
其实 我是在"流言终结者"里看到的
Yeah, I saw it on Mythbusters.
科学原理: 放热反应
好了 这些铁锈
All right, this rust,
加上从车上刮下来的铝
combined with the aluminum recovered from the van,
可以充当铝热剂
is now thermite.
真棒
Great.
用一点应该就够了
Couple pinches ought to do the trick.
这么少能融化螺帽吗?
Is that enough to melt the lug nut?
开始的时候先少放点
Well, let's start small.
不够的话再加就好
We can always add more.
螺帽 算你有本事 给我们出了这么大的难题
You put up a good fight, lug nut,
不过 你终于遇到对手(火柴)了
but you've met your match.
嘿 看啊!
Hey, look!
我们搞定那个螺帽了
The lug nut's off.
你们...
What...
你们怎么回来了?
What are you doing back?
我们的车胎爆了
We got a flat
又没法把轮胎卸下来
and couldn't get the tire off.
真同情你们
Oh, I'm sorry.
没事的
Thank you.
要是我告诉你 我帮Amy打了耳洞
If it makes you feel any better,
结果她妈妈罚她待在我衣柜里的话
I pierced Amy's ears
你会不会感觉好点
and her mom made her sit in my closet.
我们把费曼的车烧了
We blew up Feynman's van.
我爸用他的拖拉机压死了我的猪
My dad killed my pig with his tractor.
我在墨西哥和Sheldon共度了良宵
I spent the night in Mexico with Sheldon.
好吧 你赢了
You win.